# 哈喽 大家好
Hello, everybody.
# 最近我们这个豆花已经拍完了
We've recently finished shooting the douhua (aka tofu pudding) video.
# 这一期是拍的时间最长的 已经拍了个多星期了
This one's the most time-consuming one. We've been shooting for over a week.
# 今天我跟我老爸来把这个石磨
Today, my dad and I are going to move the stone mill
# 拿到老家去推一点豆花吃一下
our countryside home, and make some authentic soy curd flower .
# 还有我们一个同事过来帮忙抬
And one of our colleagues came to help carry it.
# 那个石磨比较重 有几百斤
That stone mill is so heavy. It weighs several hundred jin.
# 三四百斤吧 一起抬比较轻松一点
Three or four hundred jin (150-200kg). It's easier to move with others.
# 正好把车开过来一起拉上去 走嘛
bring the car to the door and pull it up. Let's go.
# 这个起码都有八九十斤的样子
This one weighs at least 80 to 90 jin.
# 这个要3个人一起抬
It takes three men to carry this.
# 2个人都抬得起
Two people can lift it.
# 小心手
Watch your hands.
# 这个磨盘下面这坨特别重 下面这个估计有300斤
This pile underneath the mill is very heavy, probably weighs about 300 jin.
# 那个一百斤
That one is about 100 jin.
# 那个也差不多一百斤
That one is also around 100 jin.
# 下面这个2个人也抬得动 但是有点费力
This one can be lifted by two men, but it's a bit hard to move.
# 3个人抬很轻松
It's easy for three people to carry.
# 好
good
# 你看嘛 它还要滚
See? It will roll.
# 好
good
# 干这个活没有点蛮力不行
You can't do this job without some brute strength.
# 反正干厨师也要能文能武
In order to be a good cook, you need to be a good fighter anyway.
# 对吧
right?
# 这个要不要的
Do we need this one?
# 这个要 这个是垫豆花的
Yes, this one is also for making the soy cured flower.
# 还差啥子
What's missing?
# 帕子
filter mesh
# 还有锅 那个纱布
Oh, the pot, and the filter mesh
# 锅儿安
big pot
# 你看这个锅这个铁锅啊 特别秀气啊
Look at this iron wok. It's so beautiful.
# 如果不放油这样子的话
If you don't put oil in it,
# 两三个小时就会生很多锈
in two or three hours, there'll be a lot of rust.
# 我现在放了一些油在里面
I've put some oil in it now.
# 放个几年都不会生锈
It won't rust for years.
# 这个就是有保养跟没保养区别就在这里
That's the difference between maintenance and no maintenance.
# 一点油其实不值什么钱
A little oil isn't really expensive.
# 好啦 现在我要开始出发了
All right, now I'm off.
# 回老家
back to our countryside home
# 放在这上面
Put it on here.
# 小心手哦
Watch your hands.
# 好
good
# 这边用泡沫垫哈 这个才往那边流得下去
Use a foam pad here, the juice flows that way by a slope.
# 噶 四伯爷
Right? Uncle Si.
# 对对对
Yes, yes, yes.
# 这边还要矮点
It need to be shorter here.
# 整点水来试哈就晓得了撒
We'll see if we can get some water to test it.
# 不用试得那边都高了
You don't have to try. It's too high over there.
# 不得高那边
I don't think so.
# 这哈往那边放
Put this over here.
# 那个碓窝在哪儿买的哦
Where did you get that quern-stone?
# 是借的啊
I borrowed it.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 这个要一个人搬 这个两个人搬反而不好搬
This one has to be moved by one person, it's harder by two.
# 放在这上面撒
Put it on here.
# 这上面的一坨120斤
This one weighs 120 jin (60kg).
# 称过的啊
Weighed?
# 嗯
Yes
# 要轻放这磨盘
You have to be gentle with the grindstone.
# 我们那个安哪儿
Where should we put it?
# 那不是啊
Yes
# 放这个要有技巧
It takes skill to place this.
# 不要在上面磨过去磨过来的
Don't rub it over the stone.
# 磨的话把那个齿齿（磨掉）
If you rub it, the tooth will grind off.
# 那肯定撒
That's for sure.
# 好可以了 终于现在放下来了
Okay, that's good. We finally moving them back to our house.
# 好 本期视频就到这里
Okay, that's it for this video.
# 下次推豆花吃
Next time we'll use this to make soy beans flower.
# 拜拜
bye-bye